Inventory of the Garth Family Papers 1798-1872
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Miscellaneous Material, n.d., 16 items. (Box-folder 5:5-6)
  - Miscellaneous documents within the collection but as yet uncertain of relationship to the Garth family, n.d., 8 items. (Box-folder 5:6)
    Miscellaneous documents within the collection but as yet uncertain of relationship to the Garth family include: Henry Mill's 1816 account with Bezaleel Brown; George Williams' accounts with Samuel Leitch, 1824-1829; William Garland's July 1823 fine by the clerk of Albemarle Co.; receipts by Benjamin Brown and John H. Craven; land patent on 1 April 1864 for Christian M. Shafer and C. P. Mathews; 10 April 1868 application for patent generating gas; and agreement to the sale of land on 11 April 1872.
  Series 5: Manuscript Volumes
- Manuscript Volumes, 1808-1852., 46 items. Bound and Unbound Manuscript Volumes. (Box-folder 5:7-13)
  - Garth family accounts with Samuel and James Leitch, 1808-1839., 19 items. (Box-folder 5:7)
    Merchandise includes: hardware, dyestuffs, liquor, household goods, gun powder, staples and groceries, stationery, penknives, sewing accessories, various fabrics, books, an entire set of china, (including serving dishes), parasol, fiddlestrings, various shoes, gloves, beavermitts, gents' gloves, gentleman's stockings, cotton and silk ladies' stockings, raisins and a copy of The Virginia Housewife.
  - Jesse Garth's accounts with various persons, 1822-1852., 27 items. (Box-folder 5:8-13)
    Accounts of various persons include: John R. Jones, Timberlake & Magruder, Beverly Blair, B. & J. Mosley, William W. Via, as well as others which are recorded in account books kept by Jesse Garth.
    - Jesse Garth's account book, Nov. 1822-March 1825., 1 item. (Box-folder 5:8)
      Account book showing debtors as John Benson, George Wolfe, Elijah Brown, David Isaacs, George Tool, [?] Medener, Abe Norris, Mathew Carsy, Samuel Leitch, N. Watson, [?] Coleman, Gennings Maupin, Lowel Brown, and Francis Dyer. Items involved pertain to lumber and/or farm products.
    - Jesse Garth's accounts with John R. Jones, 1828-1837., 3 items. (Box-folder 5:9)
      Accounts are for a wide variety of personal, household, and hardware merchandise, including: buckskin gloves, coal bellows, vest pattern, parasol, and square iron.
    - Jesse Garth's accounts with Timberlake & Magruder, 1830-1832., 5 items. (Box-folder 5:10)
      Accounts are for such items as bran, flour, cotton bales, plaster, freight, and drayage.
    - Jesse Garth's accounts with Beverley Blair, 1832-1834., 4 items. (Box-folder 5:11)
      Accounts pertain to the tobacco trade.
    - Jesse Garth's accounts with B. & J. Moseley, 1840-1848., 6 items. (Box-folder 5:12)
      Accounts are for a variety of household goods; grocery items and sewing and fabric accessories.
    - Jesse Garth's accounts with William W. Via, 1843-1852., 8 items. (Box-folder 5:13)
      Accounts are for a variety of customized blacksmithing products.